## **AJ Weeks**

# **Graphics Programmer**

Skärmarbrinksvägen 12 Stockholm, Sweden 121 35 (+46) 724 064 797 contact@ajweeks.com

I am an experienced graphics programmer with a strong understanding of modern realtime graphics techniques, game engine architecture, and optimization. I have solid problem solving abilities, I'm a fast learner, and I'm keen on working in interdisciplinary teams to achieve the best possible results.

### **Work Experience**

#### Avalanche Studios Group / Experienced Graphics Programmer

JAN 2022 - PRESENT, STOCKHOLM, SWEDEN

Graphics Programmer on Contraband (open world AAA in-development title). Responsibilities primarily include improving the **raytraced global illumination** and **shadow rendering** systems, maintenance of the engine, and **optimizing CPU** & GPU workloads.

Technologies used: Proprietary engine (Apex Engine) (C++, HLSL), Perforce, PIX

#### **Electric Square / Programmer**

FEBRUARY 2018 - DECEMBER 2021, BRIGHTON, UK

Four-month internship followed by full time employment as a generalist programmer. Responsibilities primarily included **engine development** (render pipeline, load times, optimization), and tool development.

Technologies used: Unity (C#), Unreal Engine 4 (C++, HLSL, Blueprints), Perforce

## Projects

#### **Flex Engine**

2017 - PRESENT

Personal game engine (C++, Vulkan). Physically-based renderer supporting features such as tessellated water, procedural terrain, GPU-based particle simulation, screen-space ambient occlusion, cascaded shadow mapping, and temporal anti-aliasing. Also includes physics simulation, audio engine, UI renderer, SDF font renderer, and scene serialization. (GitHub)

#### **Realtime Global Illumination Research**

2019 - 2021

Co-author of unpublished academic paper describing **novel**, **scalable**, **& dynamic global illumination** technique. Also responsible for implementation in production.

#### **Raymarching Workshop**

2018

Workshop given to colleagues sharing the theory and application of the raymarching rendering technique. (Course materials: <u>GitHub</u>)

#### **Education**

#### **Digital Arts and Entertainment /** Hogeschool West-Vlaanderen

AUGUST 2015 - JUNE 2018, KORTRIJK, BELGIUM

Programming-focused allround game development BSc. Courses included: Graphics, Physics, & Al programming, Applied Math & Physics, Unity & UE4, 3D Asset Creation, Rigging, Photoshop & Illustrator. Graduated Magna Cum Laude.